Come in .
What is it , Poole ?
It 's a quarter to three , sir .
And your address at the university is at 3 : 00 .
So it is , Poole .
So it is .
You know , Poole , you 're a nuisance .
Yes , sir .
But I don 't know what I should do without you .
Thank you , sir .
Your sense of duty is as impregnable as Gibraltar .
Even Bach can 't move it .
Yes , sir . Thank you , sir .
I 'm afraid you 'll be late , sir .
I see you want to get rid of me .
All right , Poole . All right .
Those are lovely roses , Poole .
Thank you , sir .
Will you wear your overcoat or cape , sir ?
Give me my cape .
Good afternoon , Jasper .
Good afternoon , sir .
- Nice day , isn 't it ? - Isn 't it , sir ?
- St. Simons . - Yes , sir .
- How do you do , sir ? - Constable .
- How are you , Stubbs ? - Very good , thank you , sir .
I won 't need you anymore today , Jasper .
Dr. Lanyon will take me where I 'm going later .
Yes , sir .
- How do you do , Dr. Jekyll ? - How do you do ?
- Hello , Hampton . - Afternoon , sir .
The auditorium is full , sir . Always is when you speak , sir .
Flattery !
- I hope Jekyll 's in form today . - He 's always in form .
The old codgers are in for another jolt .
I 'd wager your friend has something up his sleeve again , Dr. Lanyon .
Jekyll is always sensational .
Always indulging in spectacular theories .
Gentlemen ... London is so full of fog ...
that it has penetrated our minds ,
set boundaries for our vision .
As men of science , we should be curious ,
and bold enough to peer beyond it ,
into the many wonders it conceals .
I shall not dwell today on the secrets of the human body
in sickness and in health .
Today , I want to talk to you of a greater marvel .
The soul of man .
My analysis of this soul ,
the human psyche ,
leads me to believe that man is not truly one ,
but truly two .
One of him strives for the nobilities of life .
This , we call his good self .
The other , seeks an expression of impulses
that bind him to some dim animal relation with the earth .
This , we may call the bad .
These two carry out an eternal struggle in the nature of man ,
yet they are chained together .
And that chain spells repression to the evil ,
remorse to the good .
Now , if these two selves could be separated from each other ,
how much freer the good in us would be .
What heights it might scale .
And the so-called evil ,
once liberated , would fulfill itself and trouble us no more .
I believe the day is not far off , when this separation will be possible .
In my experiments , I have found that
certain chemicals have the power and the ...
Tell me , he can split me in two like a jolly amoeba .
By Jove , it 's marvelous .
I confess , it 's too much for me .
Why don 't you stay at home and send your other self to the lecture ?
To divide a human being in two ? Ridiculous !
I 'm going to try to analyze my psyche .
I didn 't expect you to agree with me , Lanyon .
Agree with you ? You talk like a lunatic .
Ha !
However I hope you 're sane enough to remember that
we 're expected for a consultation at the Duchess of Densmore 's .
- I 'm not going . - What ?
Please give the duchess my compliments and some castor oil .
Now Jekyll .
I saw her yesterday . She 's a bit bilious .
More in spirit than in body , I 'm afraid .
I 'm going along to the free wards .
My dear fellow , be reasonable .
You know how insistent the duchess was on your coming .
Heaven knows why .
You can 't neglect her for a lot of charity cases .
Can 't I , though , Lanyon ?
It 's the things one can 't do that always tempt me .
Oh , well , just as you like .
But you will remember we have a dinner engagement
at the Carews ' tonight .
- Yes , indeed . - I 'll pick you up later .
Thanks , old fellow . You 'll find me in the wards .
See you anon .
Mary , what are you doing with those crutches ?
I can 't do without them , sir .
Yes , you can do without them , Mary .
I told you yesterday .
Believe me , I can do anything for you .
I believe you , sir ,
but I can 't walk without them , sir .
Yes , you can . Give them to me .
Don 't be afraid .
Now walk , Mary . Come on . Come to me .
Yes , sir .
Walk , Mary . Come on .
All right , sir .
- I can walk , sir . - Of course you can .
I can walk , sir !
Oh ! Oh ! I can walk , sir !
I can walk , sir .
Oh !
There , there , Mrs. Lucas .
- It hurts , doesn 't it ? - Yes , sir .
Sometimes a doctor must hurt you a little to make you well .
Yes , sir .
And if a doctor thinks a slight operation is necessary ,
there 's no need to be afraid , is there ?
No , sir .
I want you to know it 's going to cure you .
I believe you , sir .
Jekyll , we haven 't much time , you know ?
I 'm sorry , Lanyon . I 'm afraid I must miss the dinner .
I 'll come afterwards for the dancing .
Why , what 's keeping you ?
I must operate on this patient at once .
Well , why not leave it to one of the house surgeons ?
They 're quite competent .
Perhaps , but I prefer to do it myself .
Will you make my excuses to General Carew and Muriel , please ?
As you like .
Oh , Lanyon . You make my excuses to the General ,
and I 'll make mine to Muriel myself .
Oh , well , all right .
Yes , Miss Muriel ?
Will it be almond cakes with coffee , Hobson ?
I 'm sorry , miss , but I don 't think so .
Oh , but we must have almond cakes .
- Send for them immediately . - Very good , miss .
What 's this ? What 's this about almond cakes ?
Dr. Jekyll likes them , Father .
You know , you 'll spoil that fiance of yours .
- I like spoiling him . - Mm , so I observe .
And what about your father ?
Well , you 're already the most spoiled darling in the world .
Dr. Lanyon .
Ah , Lanyon , delighted to see you .
Punctual for dinner , punctual in everything , eh ?
- How do you do , sir ? - What an astonishing motto , Father .
- How do you do , Muriel ? - Where 's Jekyll ?
He stayed to perform an operation .
- Oh , isn 't he coming ? - He will be in after dinner .
He asked me to make his excuses .
I hope the patient is worthy of Jekyll 's attention .
A woman in the free wards .
Free ward ?
Jekyll gives entirely too much time to his charity patients .
- Oh , I love him for that . - Nonsense , my dear .
He ought to come down to earth .
- Mr. Utterson . - Ah , Utterson .
However , I 've promised Harry the first waltz .
If he 's late , I shall be furious .
Oh , no .
You know , I 'm very glad Jekyll is late .
I 'm obliged to him for a most delightful waltz .
Thank you .
Hello , General . I 'm very sorry to be late , sir . Muriel .
Well , repentance is a virtue , Jekyll , but it 's better to be punctual .
In 40 years , I 've never been late for dinner .
It 's indeed a remarkable record , sir .
Oh , merely a matter of training , my boy .
- At the age of ... - General ?
You 've not forgotten this is our dance ?
Oh , certainly not , Lady Dakin .
I 've been looking forward to it . Uh , see you later , Jekyll .
- May I ? - I shouldn 't .
But you will .
- Was she pretty ? - Ravishing .
- Who ? - Your patient .
Oh , I was thinking of someone else .
Someone to make you late again ?
- Are you chiding me ? - Of course .
- Because you hate me ? - Of course , silly .
Well , then , will you come into the garden where I can bear it ?
- Certainly not . - Why not ?
Father . He 'd be furious .
It will do him good .
Well , he 's not looking .
He 's teaching Lady Dakin how to waltz .
- We shan 't stay long . - Just forever .
Oh , no . Not even half as long as that .
Now , my farthing , chide me , mock me , hate me ,
but don 't send me away .
Silly . Are you sorry you were late ?
- Oh , no . - You 're not ?
If I hadn 't been late , you wouldn 't have pouted .
I shall never forgive ...
If you hadn 't pouted , you wouldn 't have looked
so divinely pretty .
Do you talk this way to your patients ?
If you hadn 't looked so divinely pretty , I might have postponed ...
- Pardon ? - Not another word .
Well ?
I might have postponed telling you that I love you so much
that I don 't want to wait any longer .
I want you to marry me now .
Oh , darling , I want to with all my heart .
You know I do , but father 's so difficult .
I don 't wanna marry your father .
I don 't mind having a difficult father-in-law .
You 'd be worth it , my darling .
I don 't think you love me seriously .
Oh , I love you better than that .
I love you gaily , happily , high-heartedly .
I love you so much that I could laugh and sing and ...
Oh , no , I shouldn 't spoil it by trying to sing .
Oh , my darling ,
I shall persuade your father to let us marry now .
I can 't wait any longer .
We shall go to Devon for our honeymoon ,
and live on love and strawberries , and the sight of the sea .
- And moonlight . - Endless moonlight .
Oh , I do love you seriously .
So seriously that it frightens me .
You 've opened a gate for me into another world .
Before that , my work was everything .
I was drawn to the mysteries of science , to the unknown .
But now , the unknown wears your face .
Looks back at me with your eyes .
Darling , I wish this moment would last forever .
You can make it last , dear .
Oh , I love you .
Be near me always .
- Always ? You and I ? - Apart from the world .
I love you , darling . I love you .
Then who shall ever separate us ?
- My sweet friend . - Oh , my love . My love .
You ought to wear squeaky shoes , Hobson .
Yes , sir . Thank you , sir .
The General asks you to come into the house , Miss Muriel .
Your guests are enquiring about you .
Coming , Hobson .
- Charming evening , sir . - Glad you came , Bonner .
- Good night , Muriel . - Good night .
You looked perfectly lovely tonight , dear .
Thank you .
- Goodbye , my dear . - Goodbye .
Good night , General .
I don 't know when I 've enjoyed myself so much .
I 'm glad .
I 'll see you at tea tomorrow , dear .
Yes . I won 't forget , Lady Dakin . Good night .
- Good night . - Good night .
Ah , Jekyll , my boy . Waiting to see me ?
I beg your pardon , sir ,
but you would make Muriel and me very happy
if you 'd set an earlier date for our wedding .
I 've already announced to you
that you would be married on the anniversary of my own wedding .
That 's eight months from now , sir .
Well , what of it ?
We 've already been engaged two months , sir .
We see no reason to ...
I presume I have some rights in the matter .
Quite right , sir . That 's why we 're asking you .
Well , why this impatience ?
Hang it all , man . It isn 't done . It isn 't done .
I 'm sorry , sir , but I cannot regard that as a serious objection .
Do you hear this , Lanyon ?
Is this another evidence of your eccentricity ?
If it is eccentric to be impatient in love , sir , I am .
This is positively indecent .
Father , do you think it 's fair to keep us apart for so long ?
I waited five years for your mother .
You have a sturdy temperament , General .
Yes , yes , I pride myself on it .
Please don 't make me wait that long for Muriel .
Now , my boy , you must leave these matters to me .
There 's such a thing as decent observance , you know ?
- Good night . - Good night , sir .
- Good night , Lanyon . - Good night , sir .
Au revoir , my sweet .
Come , Lanyon .
- Good night , Muriel . - Good night .
Well , I 'm afraid you offended the General .
Offended him ?
It 's a pity I didn 't strangle the old walrus .
Did you hear him ? " Wait . Wait . "
What the devil does one wait for ?
Well , I hope the responsibilities of marriage
will sober you up .
I 'm not marrying to be sober . I 'm marrying to be drunk .
Drunk with love and life and experiments .
Your experiments are absurd , my dear fellow .
Ha ! You have no interest in science at all .
You have no dreams , no curiosity .
There are bounds beyond which one should not go .
Yes . It isn 't done , I suppose .
I tell you , there are no bounds , Lanyon .
Look at that gas lamp .
But for some man 's curiosity , we should not have had it .
London would still be lighted by linkboys .
And wait . One day , London will glow with incandescence ,
and will be so beautiful that even you will be moved by it .
Well , I find London quite satisfactory as it is ,
and I 'm not interested in your shortcuts and your byways .
But it 's in the byways that the secrets and wonders lie .
In science and in life . Look at the ...
Let go , or I 'll bash you in the jaw .
Go on , you big brute . Hit me . Hit me .
I 'll put the police on you .
You 'll put the police on me ?
Are you badly hurt ?
Oh , you poor girl .
Where does this girl live ?
Upstairs , first door to the left at the top of the stairs .
Bring her up here .
Oh , sweetheart .
Make way for the governor . Have you got her , governor ?
- Right up here ? - Yes . Look out for her head .
Oh , shut up , you lot !
What was this all about ?
Ivy Pearson , sir .
- One of Ivy Pearson 's callers ... - I can tell you ...
Now , shut up ! One of Ivy ...
That swine . Hit me , will he ?
He 'll wish he hadn 't ! He 'll wish he hadn 't !
I ain 't afraid of him , I ain 't . Blast his dirty mug !
He 's killed me , that 's what he 's done .
He 's broken me jaw and me knee , too .
I 'll get him for this .
Look where he kicked me .
It 's only a bruise .
It will be quite well in a few days .
By the way , you mustn 't wear so tight a garter . It 's bad for you .
It impedes the circulation .
It 's awful kind of you to look after me .
Anybody can see now that you 're a real gent , you are .
Now you 're the kind a woman would do something for .
You 'll be all right .
- Good night . - Oh !
- What is it ? - He 's hit me here , too , the blighter .
He 's broken me ribs , that 's what he 's done .
I 'm going to faint .
You 're not seriously hurt .
A bit of rest would do you no harm , though .
You think I ought to go to bed ?
I know of no better place for a rest .
Oh . All right .
You turn your eyes away now .
How is the pain now ?
I say !
Oh . Lanyon .
Coming .
I 'm a doctor , you know , and I 'll call that kiss my fee .
- Well ? - Hm ?
Come back soon , won 't you ?
Sorry , I 'm afraid I can 't .
Oh , yes , you can .
Soon .
- Good night . - Come back .
Come back soon , won 't you ?
Oh , yes , you can .
Soon .
Come back .
I thought your conduct quite disgusting , Jekyll .
Conduct ? Why , a pretty girl kissed me .
Should I have called the constable ?
- Even suppose I 'd liked it . - What ?
Yes .
That 's not a matter of conduct , but of elementary instinct .
You ought to control those instincts .
Are you pretending that you either can or do ?
We may control our actions , but not our impulses .
Perhaps you 've forgotten you 're engaged to Muriel .
Forgotten it ?
Can a man dying of thirst forget water ?
And do you know what would happen to that thirst if it were denied water ?
If I understand you correctly , you sound almost indecent .
What names you give things .
Well , why aren 't you frank enough to admit
that other indecent self in you ?
No . You prefer to hide it , pretend it isn 't there .
- You have to accept certain things . - I don 't want to accept them .
I want to be clean , not only in my conduct ,
but in my innermost thoughts and desires .
- There 's only one way to do it . - How ?
Separate the two natures in us .
Oh , that absurd theory of yours .
I tell you , it 's unscientific
not to admit the possibility of anything .
- Oh , you 're mad . - Mad , eh , Lanyon ?
Oh , we 'll see .
We 'll see .
Come in .
What is it , Poole ?
Begging your pardon for the intrusion , sir ,
but did you sleep last night , sir ?
Don 't worry about me .
Yes , sir , but you had only a cup of tea for breakfast for three days .
Your health .
Now , Poole , you didn 't come here to enquire after my health , did you ?
One of General Carew 's servants brought this , sir .
Miss Muriel is scolding me for having missed a dinner last night .
Yes , sir .
Go to her at once and tell her that
I shall certainly come to dinner tomorrow night .
Very good , sir .
Ah !
Marry me now .
I can 't wait any longer .
Positively indecent .
Look where he kicked me .
Your conduct was disgusting .
It isn 't done . It isn 't done .
Pity I didn 't strangle him .
Strangle him .
Indecent . Indecent .
Can a man dying of thirst forget water ?
Disgusting .
You 're mad . Mad .
Come back soon , won 't you ?
Come back .
Free !
Free at last !
Ah !
Mad eh , Lanyon ? Eh , Carew ?
You hypocrites . Deniers of life .
If you could see me now , what would you think , hm ?
Ah !
Who is there ? Who is there ?
Who 's there ?
Dr. Jekyll ?
Dr. Jekyll , sir ?
Is that you ?
Do you hear me , sir ?
Please let me in , sir . Let me in !
I beg your pardon , sir .
I thought I heard a strange voice .
That 's quite all right , Poole . There was someone here .
A friend of mine .
His name is Hyde . Mr. Hyde .
He 's just gone out the back door .
Yeah .
Marry me now , my darling .
You don 't know how much I need you .
I want to with all my heart , but Father ...
I 'll speak to him . I 'll convince him .
No , no . Let me talk to him .
I 'll try to change his mind while we 're away .
- Away ? - Yes .
Oh , darling , I 've dreaded telling you ,
but Father 's taking me to Bath tomorrow .
He has no right to take you away from me .
Why must we put up with this ?
You want to marry me ?
With all my heart .
We 'll marry without his consent .
Say you will , my darling .
We 'll go to Paris for our honeymoon .
We 'll be so gloriously happy
that even the French will be jealous of us .
I 'm so thrilled and tempted ,
but I don 't want to hurt my father .
It 's only a little hurt to his vanity .
You 'll do me a greater hurt if you refuse .
Do be patient just a little while .
I 'm sure I can persuade him while we 're gone .
- But , Muriel ... - Darling , don 't you love me enough ...
to wait a little while ?
Of course .
Of course , I love you enough , dear .
I 'll wait .
Wait .
Come in .
A letter from Bath , sir .
Miss Muriel won 't be home for another month .
- Can 't even go to see her . - I 'm sorry to hear it , sir .
Another month .
I beg your pardon , sir ,
but may I suggest that you ought to amuse yourself .
Amuse myself ? Now , what do you suggest , Poole ?
Well , you ought to go out , sir .
London offers many amusements for a gentleman like you , sir .
Yes , but a gentleman like me daren 't take advantage of them , Poole .
Gentlemen like me have to be very careful of what they do and say .
- That 's all . - Yes , sir .
Here ! Here !
What are you after down there ?
Ah ! I was calling on the young lady who occupies the little nest .
- If it 's Ivy Pearson you mean ... - Yeah .
- She ain 't in . - Oh .
Do you know where I can find her ?
If I was wanting her , I 'd try the Variety Music Hall .
Oh ! Thank you .
I thank you .
You get out ! What do you take me for ?
Get out !
- Stay out of here . - I didn 't do nothing , mister .
A bottle of champagne and be quick about it .
What are you staring at ?
Nothing , sir .
Well , what are you waiting for ?
A tip , eh ? Get out !
Blighter .
- Sorry , sir . I 'm sorry . - You swine !
He 's a rum 'un .
Let 's have a drink .
Champagne Ivy is my name
Good for any game at night , my boy
You come and join me in a spree
I will .
You 're a bit of something to look at and listen to , dearie .
Not half bad , so they say .
You ain 't conceited , are you ?
Well , I has me points .
Hey , Charlie !
Blimey , there 's Irv . I 'll be back in half a mo .
Hey . Hey , you . Hey .
Tell that wench in black to come over and have a bottle of wine with me .
- Yes , sir . - That 's right .
The gent in the box wants you to have wine with him .
Oh , he does , does he ?
What of it ?
Well , you 'd better come if you know what 's good for you .
He ain 't one to be trifled with , he ain 't .
Strike me pink . You interest me .
I 'll take a chance .
- Where is he ? - I 'll take you to him .
This is indeed a great honor . I noticed you as you came in , my dear .
" There , " I said to myself ,
" is too pretty a girl to waste on such a companion . "
Ah , but you are pretty .
And what a figure , my dear .
What a figure .
A glass of champagne .
To you . To you , my dear .
To your beauty , mm ?
- I must be going now . - Going ?
- Where ? - Uh , home .
You call that home ?
That pigsty of yours in Baffin 's Court ?
Sty , is it ? You come off that .
Oh , I like you when your temper 's up , my dear .
How do you know where I live ?
I saw you on the street and followed you .
Ah , my pretty , you deserve better than that .
You ought to live in a place worthy of you .
Buckingham Palace , I suppose .
That 's the spirit I like .
Sit down , my dear . Sit down just for a moment , eh ?
You should have a place that would set off that fine body of yours ,
yellow hair and pale face .
Clothes to match , too , my dear . Silk , eh ?
And a bracelet or two , eh ?
Champagne to drink , eh ?
How would you like that ?
And how am I to get it ?
How do you think you 're going to get it , my bright little bird , hm ?
Uh ...
I am no gentleman , no , but I have money .
Perhaps my looks don 't please you .
Well , you ain 't no beauty .
Quite right . I am no beauty .
Perhaps you prefer a gentleman , eh ?
One of those fine-mannered , virtuous , and honorable gentlemen .
One of those canting hypocrites
who like your legs , but talk about your garter .
What are you talking about ?
Oh , my poor little innocent .
It doesn 't know what I 'm talking about , eh ?
Well , well , well , it 's afraid of me , isn 't it ?
No ! I ain 't afraid of you .
- Aren 't you ? Good . - Hey , you .
Trying to steal my girl , are you , you dirty blighter ?
Come back , you . I 'll fix you for this , you wench .
Sit down ! Sit down .
I 'll knock your blooming head off !
Get out of here , you ...
You couldn 't have done it .
Couldn 't I , though ? Why not ?
This place was just made for it .
- Oh , now . - Here , stop that . Let me go .
- Oh , no . You 're not going anywhere . - Let me go . I 'm going .
I 'm going home !
Sit down .
Forgive me , my dear .
You see , I hurt you because I love you .
I want you .
And what I want , I get .
I grant you , I am no beauty ,
but under this exterior ...
you 'll find a very flower of man .
Look at me .
Do you suppose I 'd let anybody stand in my way ?
I love you . I love you . Do you understand ?
You 'll come with me , eh ?
You 'll come with me .
Come in , sir .
I presume your master is out .
Yes , sir . So he is , sir .
He 's always out when I call .
Tell your master I 've had a letter from General Carew .
He tells me that Dr. Jekyll has not replied to
any of Miss Muriel 's letters .
- She 's worried about him . - I 'll tell him , sir .
Anyway , I 'm relieved to know he 's not confined to his bed .
Begging your pardon , sir .
It 's my opinion that my master isn 't well .
He hardly sees his patients , sir .
I haven 't seen him myself for days at a time .
He often comes and goes by the back door of the laboratory , sir .
I must be going , Poole . Good day .
Who 's there ?
It 's me , dearie , your landlady .
Come in , Mrs. Hawkins .
Oh , how are you , dearie ?
You don 't have to answer .
I can see for myself you ain 't as fit as you ought to be ,
and no wonder .
Oh , here , dearie . I brought you the newspaper .
Thank you , Mrs. Hawkins .
Oh , you 're having a cup of tea , I see .
If you don 't mind , dearie , I 'll sit with you a minute .
I 'm that done in .
Oh , will you have a cup of tea , Mrs. Hawkins ?
Thank you , dearie . I don 't mind if I do .
After all , a neighbor 's a neighbor , says I.
Here 's a bit of a surprise for you .
He 's a lodger of mine , and a very likely lad he is , too .
His name 's Arvis ,
and he says to me , says he ,
" Who 's the pretty lass what has the parlor ?
I wonder if she 'd be inclined to drop in at the music hall with me
one of these fine nights ?
You ask her , " says he .
Now , my advice , dearie ...
No , no , no . I don 't want to hear any more about it .
Oh . Afraid of what Hyde will do to you , ain 't you ?
No , I ain 't afraid .
If that blighter was my man , he wouldn 't dare to lay a hand on me .
Not if he knowed what was good for him .
He 's a brute . That 's what he is .
And my advice , dearie ...
- What do you want ? - I 've come for the rent , sir .
You 'll get it when it 's due .
Very good , sir .
What did that filthy harridan want ?
She ... brought me the paper .
- What else ? - Nothing .
You aren 't lying to me , are you , my little bird ?
No , no , no , I ain 't lying to you .
If I ever catch you lying , these are a trifle to what you 'll get .
A trifle !
Come here .
Sit down ...
so that I can look at you , my sweetling .
Say it aloud .
What do you mean ?
Don 't you think I can read your thoughts , you trull ?
You hate me , don 't you ?
I 'm not good enough for you !
I 'm not a nice , kind gentleman like that ...
Nice , kind gentlemen who are so good to look at and so ...
Cowards ! Weaklings !
Tell me you hate me . Please , my lamb .
Please , my dear , sweet , pretty little bird ,
tell me that you hate me .
I don 't know what you mean .
Don 't you , my lamb ?
Then you don 't hate me , eh ?
- No , sir . - Ah !
If you don 't hate me , you must love me . Isn 't that so , my little one ?
- Isn 't it ? - Yes , sir .
Ah ! How you must love me .
I want to hear you say it .
Say it . Come , my wench . Say it ! Say it !
- Say it ! - Yes , sir !
I have got bad news for you , my dear .
Very bad .
I , uh ...
I 'm going away for a few days .
And upon my word , if you don 't seem pleased .
You are pleased , aren 't you ?
- No , sir , I ain 't pleased . - You are pleased !
But pleasure is brief in this world , my sweet .
And yours is most uncertain , because ...
you don 't know when I 'll be back , do you ?
- No , sir . - " No , sir . No , sir . "
Remember , you belong to me , do you hear ?
You belong to me .
If you do one thing that I don 't approve of while I 'm gone ,
the least little thing , mind you ...
I 'll show you what horror means .
Are you going now ?
- Tonight ? - Now ?
Why , my dear , I 'm surprised at you .
What a leave-taking that would be .
You wouldn 't have me go tonight , would you ?
Would you let me go tonight ?
Would you ?
No , sir .
Of course not .
Quite unworthy of our great love . Hmm ?
No , my dear , I 'm not going now .
I 'm going to spend the evening here with you .
Just as you want . Say , " Just as I want . "
Say " Just as I want . "
Just as I want !
That 's right , my little bird .
The last evening is always the sweetest , you know .
And what a farewell this one will be .
What a farewell .
I don 't know whether I shall be able to tear myself away from you at all .
Perhaps I shall go only as far as the door ...
and the sight of your tears will bring me back .
Does that please you , my dear ?
Yes , sir .
Why don 't you show it , then ?
Why don 't you dance ? Why don 't you sing ?
Sing , my dear !
Sing , my little pigeon !
Get up and sing ! You hear ?
Sing !
Champagne Ivy is my name
Good for any game at night , my boy
Good for ...
Look , my darling , how tight your garter is .
You mustn 't wear it so tight .
It will bruise your pretty , tender flesh .
Your tea , sir .
Thank you , Poole .
I shall be going out presently .
Miss Muriel is returning to London today .
Oh , very good , sir .
See this key , Poole ?
Yes , sir .
It 's the key to the back door of the laboratory , sir .
I 'll have no further use for it .
From now on , I 'll use only the front door .
Yes , sir .
Deliver this to Miss Ivy Pearson , Diadem Court , Soho .
Any message , sir ?
None . Deliver it and come away .
Hyde will kill you one day .
I wish he would kill me . I wish he would .
Why don 't you run away ?
Where to ? He 'd find me wherever I was .
Then why don 't you go to the police ? They 'd fix this Hyde man .
No no , I 'm afraid .
There ain 't nobody to help me . Nobody .
Who cares what becomes of the likes of me ?
Come in .
Miss Ivy Pearson ?
That 's me .
This is from my master , Dr. Jekyll , miss .
Not Dr. Henry M. Jekyll ?
Quite so . He said there is no answer . Good day , miss .
I don 't know Dr. Jekyll .
Fifty pounds !
Well , he knows you , dearie .
Strike me pink !
Fifty pounds from the celebrated Dr. Jekyll .
He 's a grand gentleman .
Always helping them what needs help .
Now , dearie , he sends you fifty pounds .
Shows he takes an interest in you .
Now , why don 't you go and thank the gentleman proper ?
Then you could tell him all about this here Hyde business .
He 'll tell that blighter what 's what .
You 'll see if he don 't .
You made me suffer so .
Now you tell me nothing .
I tell you no man ever needed another ,
or loved another as I need and love you .
I don 't know what to say ...
but if you 'd been ill that would have been different .
I was ill , my darling .
Then why didn 't you let me know ? I should have come at once .
I wasn 't ill in body . I was ill in soul .
The sufferings of the spirit are so difficult to communicate .
Even to those who love you .
Do you think there 's anything that has to do with you
that I wouldn 't understand ?
I know that you 're gentle and understanding , but ...
I can 't explain to you .
I have played with dangerous knowledge .
I 've walked a strange and terrible road .
Help me to find my way back .
Oh , my sweet .
When you 're all mine to love and keep ,
I shall be patient as the earth with you .
Then let 's not wait any longer . Let us be married at once .
I want to with all my heart .
Take me . Take me soon .
I love you , and I want to help you .
Muriel ?
Muriel .
I didn 't expect to find you here , sir .
I 've just made my profoundest apologies to Muriel .
- Oh , and what about me ? - Permit me to make them to you , sir ,
and to trust that you will be indulgent .
You haven 't explained anything yet , sir .
I ... I was not quite myself , sir .
- I was ill . - Ill ? Ill .
Well , in that case , of course , we 'll say no more about it .
Thank you , sir . May I take further advantage of your indulgence ?
Yes . What is it ?
Your consent to our early marriage .
Oh , please , Father , do say yes . Harry needs me .
- I 've already told you ... - But we 're too unhappy apart .
Oh , please , Father . This is the most important request of my life .
I see no reason to change my mind .
Isn 't my happiness reason enough ?
I assure you , sir , you will have no cause to regret it .
Well , to be frank , Jekyll ,
I 'm not at all satisfied with your conduct .
I don 't understand you , sir .
I expect a man in your position to observe certain traditions .
I want to see you more settled down
before I entrust my daughter to your care .
You 're too flighty , too impatient ...
Believe me , sir , these faults will be corrected .
I give you my word of honor .
Please , Father . My whole life is concerned .
- Hm . Hm . - Please ?
Well ...
Well , well , I see you 're overriding me .
Jekyll , remember you gave me your word of honor .
Yes , sir .
Very well . You shall be married next month .
Come to dinner tomorrow , eh ?
And we 'll make a formal announcement to our friends .
Oh , thank you , sir . By Jove , you 've made me happy !
I could sing or dance , or roll a hoop ...
- Jekyll , no , no , no , no , no . - No , I beg your pardon , sir .
Until tomorrow , my sweet .
Goodb ... good ... goodbye , sir .
Goodbye .
Ah , Poole , my dear fellow .
I 'm a very happy man !
I 'm happy to hear it .
Ah , happy , by Jove ! Happy !
" Jocund Day Stands Tip Toe on the Misty Mountain Tops . "
Yes , sir .
May I take your cape , sir ?
You may , Poole , you may , my dear fellow .
I 'm going to be married , Poole . Next month .
Think of it . In a few weeks , she 'll be under this very roof ,
in this very room , as my wife .
Think of it , Poole , and let me see your face .
Yes , sir ! I beg to congratulate you , sir !
Ah-ha !
" If music be the food of love , play on . "
Yes .
I beg your pardon , sir ,
but Miss Pearson is waiting for you in the consulting room .
Miss Pearson ?
The young woman that you sent the envelope to , sir .
- What does she want ? - She wishes to consult you , sir .
- Very well . Show her in here . - Yes , sir .
Why , it 's you , sir !
So it is .
Now who would have thought it ?
Who would have thought that I 'd find the celebrated Dr. Jekyll ?
So it was you who sent me this money ?
Yes .
The minute I laid eyes on you , I knew you had a kind heart .
But whatever made you do it , sir ?
Someone told me that you needed it .
- Who , sir ? - Doesn 't matter .
The important thing is that you have it .
And you 're welcome to it .
I can 't take it , sir .
- Why not ? - Why ? Why ?
Here 's why ! Here 's why !
Pretty , ain 't it ?
It 's a whip , that 's what it is . A whip .
Horrible . Horrible !
I 'll give you a lotion to soothe that .
Thank you , sir , but a lotion won 't do the trick , sir .
No , sir . It 's more than that , sir .
I need help , I do . I can 't stand it anymore .
- What is it , my dear ? - It 's Hyde , sir . Hyde .
It 's him that 's done that , and more as I can 't tell you , sir .
He ain 't human , he ain 't , sir . He 's a beast .
He won 't let me go , and I 'm afraid ...
I 'm afraid to run away .
I 've tried to drown myself ...
but I can 't .
And if you don 't help me ...
You as has the kindest heart in the world , sir ...
then give me poison , so I can kill myself .
Why didn 't you seek help before ? Why didn 't you go to the police ?
I was afraid .
You don 't know him , sir . He ain 't a man . He 's a devil .
He knows what you 're thinking about , he does .
I 'm afraid of him . I 'm afraid of him now !
If he knows that I 've been here today , I don 't know what he 'll do !
It won 't be anything human , sir .
Oh , save me . Save me !
Keep him off me . I 'll do anything you ask .
I 'll be your slave !
Oh , help me !
You won 't let me go back to him , will you , sir ?
You 're an angel .
You 're an angel , sir .
I 'll do anything you like .
I ain 't as bad as you think .
And I ain 't a bad looker , either .
I 'll work for you . I 'll slave for you .
I 'll love you .
You ... you liked me once , didn 't you ?
Why don 't you ?
I give you my word ...
that you will never be troubled with Hyde again .
No , no , sir . He 'll come back and he 'll kill me , sir !
He will not come back . I 'll see to it .
But you don 't know him , sir . He ain 't human , he ain 't .
I 've given you my word , and that I never break .
You will not see Hyde again .
Believe me .
I believe you , sir .
I believe you .
You must go now .
Yes , sir .
Begging your pardon , sir . Will it be a large affair ?
Not particularly . General Carew 's cronies , chiefly .
They wouldn 't regard the marriage as authentic ,
unless it were formally announced at a dinner table , you know ?
Perhaps soon , sir , you 'll be giving a formal dinner yourself , sir .
I may , Poole , I may .
- Should I call a hansom , sir ? - No , thank you .
A walk through the park will do me good .
Yes , sir .
- We 're early . - I 'm glad you are .
My dear , of course , I wish you all happiness . All happiness .
- Oh , thank you , Dr. Lanyon . - How are you , General ?
" Thou wast not born for death , immortal Bird ! "
" No hungry generations tread thee down . "
" Thou wast not born for death ... "
Oh , no . Oh !
Oh . Oh .
But it is dead . Dead !
Rather late .
It 's very queer that he 's not here .
I don 't understand it .
Of course , he 's a very busy man . He was probably detained .
Do you think anything could have happened to Harry , Mr. Utterson ?
On a night like this , my dear ? Nonsense .
Why is he late then ?
There , there , my dear .
It 's not his lateness , it 's your impatience .
He 'll be along presently .
I hope so .
Here 's hoping that Hyde rots wherever he is ,
and burns where he ought to be .
And here 's hoping that
Dr. Jekyll will think of Ivy once in a while .
He 's an angel , he is .
Here 's to you , my angel .
You thought I wouldn 't come back , didn 't you ?
You took the word of that sniveling hypocrite Jekyll against mine .
Jekyll 's word against Hyde 's , eh ?
I know everything you do and everything you think !
You went down on your knees before him .
The man I hate more than anybody in the world !
- No ! - No ?
" I 'll slave for you . I 'll love you . You 're an angel , sir . "
You wanted him to love you , didn 't you ?
I 'll give you a lover now .
His name is death !
No , no , it ain 't so ! No !
It ain 't so !
Oh , ain 't it so , my little bird ?
My little starling .
Why , you lying wench !
You 've got his money here now !
You must be the devil .
There was nobody there but me and Dr. Jekyll .
He wouldn 't have told you ! No , he wouldn 't !
Wouldn 't he , though ? Wouldn 't he ?
Listen , my dear . Listen !
I 'm going to let you into a secret .
A secret so great ,
that those who share it with me cannot live !
I am ...
I am the angel whom you wanted to slave for and love !
And I 'm going to take you in my arms now and hold you close !
Close , my little lamb .
My dove ! My bird !
Ha !
There , my sweet .
There , my dove .
There , my little bride .
Isn 't Hyde a lover after your own heart ?
Oh , there 's something horrible happening up there !
- Did you hear it ? - Go up , I tell you .
- Come on . - Something horrible ...
- You murdering devil ! - Help , help !
Stop ! Stop him !
A monster did this .
I know him . I know him . His name is Hyde .
Let me in . I 'm a friend of Dr. Jekyll .
Dr. Jekyll isn 't at home .
Oh , I know it , you fool !
He told me to wait for him .
You 'll have to come back later .
Open that door , or I 'll break it in !
My dear , I can 't tell you how sorry I am .
And I hope with all my heart
that Jekyll will have something to say for himself .
- Good night , sir . - Good night , Lanyon .
I 'll cane that scoundrel Jekyll if I ever set eyes on him again .
No , Father . Something terrible must have happened .
I 'm sure he can explain . I believe in him .
I forbid you to see this man again .
I love him , Father , and I 'm going to marry him .
Muriel , you will have nothing more to do with that man .
- Give me pencil and paper . Quick ! - Yes , sir .
Hey , you . Be ready to carry a message for me .
Yes , sir .
- Hello , Briggs . - Good evening , sir .
I beg your pardon , sir .
A messenger brought this a little while ago .
- Really ? - He said it was very important .
I 'm going out , Briggs , but I 'll be back soon .
Yes , sir .
Oh . You may go to bed .
- I won 't need you anymore tonight . - Thank you , sir .
- I come from Dr. Jekyll . - Come in .
Have you got it ?
Follow me .
Come , sir .
You forget I have not the pleasure of your acquaintance .
I beg your pardon , Dr. Lanyon .
You know what I came for . Dr. Jekyll sent me .
It 's important . A package .
- Is it here ? - Yes .
- Here it is . - Ah !
But before I give it to you ,
I must be assured of Dr. Jekyll 's safety .
- Where is he ? - He 's alive and safe .
- I 'll take these to him . - I 'll go with you .
I must see for myself that Jekyll is ...
This is no concern of yours !
I warn you not to meddle .
You will take me to Dr. Jekyll , or you will not leave this room .
I warn you , Lanyon , to let me go .
And I warn you , if you make another step towards that door ,
I 'll shoot you .
You don 't know what you 're doing . I can 't tell you anything .
Ask Jekyll tomorrow if you want to .
I 'll be sure of Dr. Jekyll 's safety , or I 'll make you answer for it .
For the last time , Lanyon , will you let me go ?
For the last time , no .
Very well , Lanyon .
This be on your own head .
Now , Lanyon ...
will you let me take this glass and leave without further question ?
I 've gone too far not to see this through to the end .
Think before you decide , I tell you !
Do you want to be left as you are ...
or do you want your eyes and your soul to be blasted
by a sight that would stagger the devil himself ?
I 'm not to be persuaded by this rigmarole .
Very well , Lanyon .
Remember your vows to your profession .
What you are about to see is a secret you are sworn not to reveal .
And now , you who have sneered at the miracles of science ,
you who have denied the power of man to look into his own soul ,
you who have derided your superiors ...
Look !
Look .
Oh !
I can 't believe what I 've seen .
I don 't understand .
I 'm in your hands to do with as you wish .
Horrible . Horrible .
I 'm a murderer , Lanyon . Help me . Help me .
There is no help for you , Jekyll .
You 've committed the supreme blasphemy .
I warned you .
I told you that no man could violate the traditions of his kind
and not be damned .
That I still do not believe .
Don 't be my inquisitor , Lanyon . Don 't judge me . Help me , if you will .
- I 'm at your mercy . - There is no help for you here ...
or mercy beyond .
You 're a rebel ...
and see what it has done for you .
You 're in the power of this monster that you 've created .
I 'll never take that drug again .
Yes , but you told me you became that monster tonight
not of your own accord .
It will happen again .
Never . I 'm sure of it . I 'll fight it . I 'll conquer it .
Too late . You cannot conquer it .
It has conquered you .
No , no , no . I 'll fight it .
I know it will not happen again .
Oh , help me .
You 'll promise at least never to mix this drug again ?
With all my heart .
And what about ... Muriel ?
I 'll give her up .
I 'll go to her tomorrow .
Set her free .
Oh , God ... this I did not intend .
I saw a light ...
but I could not see where it was leading .
I have trespassed on your domain .
I 've gone further than man should go .
Forgive me . Help me .
I beg your pardon , sir . Dr. Jekyll is calling .
Jekyll ?
Tell him we 're not at home , Hobson .
Father , no , for my sake .
He dares to enter this house ?
Neither you nor I have the right to judge him .
Judge him ? Are you mad ?
The fellow 's a blackguard .
I won 't hear you say one word against him .
- Show him in , Hobson . - But I ...
Father .
I don 't know what he 's done ,
but I know he 's a finer and greater person than any of us .
- Silence ! I won 't hear another word . - I shall say it .
We 've never understood him . We 've never tried to understand him .
You tried to bend him to your will and I haven 't fought for him enough .
I don 't know what 's happened to him , but I know he 's been suffering .
And it 's our fault . Mine more than yours .
I love him , and I 'm going to help him .
This is preposterous ! I 'll have nothing to do with it .
I can offer you no welcome , sir .
Had the matter been left in my hands , I would have turned you from the door .
Forgive me .
Forgive me , Muriel .
Oh , my darling , are you ill ?
Oh , what is it ?
What ? What is it ?
My sweet , why are you suffering so ?
- Tell me . Tell me what it is . - Tell you ?
I 've come to tell you .
I 've come to ... to set you free .
- Set me free ? - Yes . Yes .
What are you saying ?
Oh , if you ever loved me , tell me what 's wrong .
Everything 's wrong .
I ... I no longer ...
have any claim on you .
- But that 's for me to say . - No . No .
Oh , my darling , I beg you to tell me . What is it ?
No . No , you don 't have to explain anything .
Whatever it is , I know you 've done nothing base or mean .
Oh , please , my dear !
Please ... please , angel of God ...
don 't say anymore .
I set you free .
Darling , is that all you have to say to me ?
- Don 't you want me any longer ? - Want you ?
I want you so that I can envy the damned .
I am damned .
You don 't know what you 're saying .
Do you think I 'd let you go ?
Only tell me that you love me and I 'm yours .
Oh , don 't keep anything from me , darling .
- I love you , and I 'll help you . - Oh , my love .
My darling . My beautiful .
If I could take you in my arms ...
If I could only touch you ...
Oh , think of it .
I daren 't even touch you ever again ...
in this world or the next .
Oh , what are you hiding from me ?
Oh , trust me , believe in me . I 'll help you .
No . I 'm beyond help , Muriel !
I 'm in hell !
I ... I 'm in hell .
I must give you up !
- But I won 't let you . - No .
I 'll go with you wherever you say .
I 'll help you no matter what it is .
If I ... if I could only have you ,
I 'd give my soul , but I ... I have no soul .
I 'm beyond the pale !
I 'm one of the living dead !
Oh , I won 't let you go !
My poor , dear , suffering love .
Be quiet . Rest . Don 't say anymore .
Be quiet and rest . Rest .
Be quiet . Don 't say anymore , darling .
Oh , let me go . Let me go quickly .
No , no , I love you . I won 't let you go .
I love you .
Oh , sweetheart .
No ! No !
I give you up because I love you so .
This is my proof . This is my penance .
Do you hear , oh , God ?
This is my penance !
Oh , God . Oh , God .
Don 't let me . Don 't let me . Save me . Save me .
Why , dar ...
Help me !
- Father , help ! - Hey !
Oh , you ...
Hobson ! Hobson !
Hobson , get him !
You , out !
Help ! Help ! Police ! Police !
You stay here . I 'll follow him .
There he goes !
This way , Officer .
Stop him !
Stop ! Police !
This is the weapon , Doctor .
I know whose cane this is .
I can take you to the man .
- Break it down ! - Open in the name of the law .
Come on , Bill . Give it your shoulder .
Ugh !
This one 's locked , too .
- Open in the name of the law . - He 's in there .
- Break it down ! Break it down ! - Open in the name of the law .
Where is he ?
He 's gone out there , through the backdoor .
Don 't stand there staring , you fool !
Yes , sir . Yes , sir .
The door down there 's locked on the outside .
Well , then go out through the front of the house .
Come on , Stonie .
- You stay here . - Wait .
He has escaped , sir .
Your man has not escaped .
There .
There he is . There 's your man .
But , Doctor , this is impossible .
I know it is , but there 's your man .
I 'm sorry , sir . You appear to be serious , but ...
Look !
Hold him ! Hold him !
Hold him . Hold him .
Guard that door .
Guard that door there .
Don 't let him get away .
Look out !
Come on , boys .
Drop that knife !
Dr. Jekyll .